# **Babalola Opeyemi Daniel**

babaloladanielope@gmail.com github repo +2349054556359

#### Introduction

I have a blend of technical skills and experience that cuts across several stacks which makes me not just incredibly versatile, but also with a deep knowledge and understanding of applications and systems architectures

I have worked and still work with some of the world's leading tech, web3, and blockchain services. Notable amongst these is Binance, and Bundle Africa. I also have led multiple engineering teams, across multiple tech stacks.

Having transitioned to Tech from Finance and the Corporate sector, I have amassed specific skill sets that guarantee efficiency at the highest level. I am exceptionally creative, innovative, with extensive problem solving, communication, management and analytical skills. My mind has been equipped as a result of the constant accumulation of knowledge and skills, which in turn, has honed my ability to be a more than average Backend/Blockchain dev..

# **Work Experience**

## **Devops Engineer**

Learnerkia Contract

- I worked on configuring NGINX servers to allow for creation of sub-domains on the fly, generated and configured SSL certificates for all existing and to-be-created domains using certbot, rewrote and redirected server so that each client has a customized experience while using the application. I did this with minimal code changes, and without interruption of the production servers
- I oversaw and reconfigured the deployment process/CI-CD architecture of the company, and curated a more professional, and standardized deployment process.
- I helped the company save a lot of server/deployment costs by reducing the number of instances/droplets their applications are being deployed on from 6 to 2, while improving the deployment process and the network latency.
- I also reviewed their app codebase, modified and recommended changes to them, in order to follow standard code quality conventions, and also improved application security protocols.
- I configured the server load balancing algorithm, implementing it in their index backend service, while using NGINX to also serve as a load balancer to distribute requests equally and as required between their deployed servers.

## **Software Engineering Backend (Lead)**

GipperPay

2022 - Present

• I single handedly wrote and deployed the authentication service that handles authentication for user and service requests to the entire suite of **microservices** that makes up the application, taking into account the dynamics of each service, while still allowing for addition of new services, and also scalability of users.

- I led the deployment of all our services on AWS, created and updated **AWS IAM** users with terraform, created and configured **EC2 instances**, configured Load balancers using NGINX to make requests to all server instances, and also worked on deploying some of our Dockerized applications using **NGINX** as a load balancer too.
- I lead the backend and devops team(5) to develop products and services around crypto-currency payments for ecommerce platforms, SMEs, and large businesses who intend to adopt crypto as a means of payment, and remit the same in fiat.
- I led the integration of multiple payment providers, including flutterwave, paystack, kuda, korapay with the application, which allows for the remitting of payments to users in fiat.
- I developed a **weighted round robin balancing algorithm/service** that handles all requests to integrated service providers, managing and distributing requests efficiently between providers.
- I also oversaw core infrastructural decisions on how the backend of the application should be. These were not limited to deployment routes, CI/CD techniques, **Github Actions**, AWS services, **Digital Ocean** etc.

### **Software Engineering(Backend)**

Binance/Bundle Africa 2021 - 2023

- Working with the team of Binance's and Bundle Africa's backend, blockchain and front-end developers in the "Back-Office" team of both firms. I worked on core services, and also wrote and still write code that implements all their other micro-services.
- Working with the Engineering support team which provides assistance to the CX team for customer support issues requiring backend, frontend and blockchain engineering fixes, particularly issues relating to **delayed on-chain/off-chain deposits/withdrawals,** recovering **failed/pending crypto deposits** across multiple networks, failed transactions due to some bugs in the backend architecture which i also was responsible for fixing.
- I am one of the core developers who worked on one of the most vital projects of the firm, a service named Cashlink. This is a Fiat-Crypto/P2P service used by the app, but needed to be made open to other firms, the first client being **Binance**. We worked on creating it as an open API service to be made available to the public, using a blend of **NodeJS/Typescript** and **Java/SpringBoot**, and did this within a very strict timeline of 1 month. **Cashlink currently processes about \$1.5M weekly.**
- I was also primarily responsible for revamping the Cashlink Website which was written with **ReactJS**, and also using some other tools such as Materialize CSS, Bootstrap, etc.
- I worked with the backend and blockchain team to migrate Bundle's former crypto wallet system, in which the creation and management of crypto wallets, generation of addresses was done by Bundle itself. We migrated our wallet system to a 'Smart Wallet' system, implementing Binance's wallet system/apis and architecture.
- Worked directly with the Head of Engineering to curtail In-app and Blockchain fraudulent claims of the users/criminals by breaking down code components of phishing sites/programs.
- I was part of the backend team who worked on a **crypto/blockchain** social media platform to be part of the Bundle's offerings to the users. I worked on content processing, profile and feed service, but specifically creating a group service (on the social media platform), which creates groups for users of

similar interests and curates content and posts in those groups depending on the interests of the users, while still implementing the administrative functionalities of this service in another service(Back-Office).

• Worked with the backend back-office team on building a web application for the mobile app which provides the same services and functions as the Bundle mobile application. Task was front-end heavy so I was writing a lot of **ReactJS**.

## **Project and Operations/Back-End Dev**

Dev Clusters

2020

- I organize individual devs, on the basis of their skill level and stacks into clusters, and act as a supervisor, supervising codes, deployments, and technologies used by each cluster.
- Writing and developing the back-end API for the networking of the teams/clusters using Java/Kotlin with Springboot and Gradle for core services, NodeJS, Express as a framework for some others, MySQL as the db, and Oauth/GoogleAuth for user authentication.
- I am part of the team developing the implementation and deployment of the startup's services using Cloud Architecture(AWS), while also working on the "Dev Clusters' API Documentation".

#### **Backend Developer(Remote)**

SpinYoga Inc

2018 to 2021

- I reviewed, modified and updated HTML, CSS and JS codes, after Github modifications by the network of devs working on said project.
- I single handedly worked on creating and deploying the backend architecture, including the creation of a blog, fitness and scheduling application, which was integrated, and the front end code in ReactJS.
- I was part of a team that implemented a revised and space optimized session management code structure for users.

### **Open Source Contributions**

- Spring Data Rest
- Leaflet: A JS library for mobile friendly interactive maps
- Java Design Patterns
- Microsoft Typescript

#### Stacks and Skills

- Java with Spring-boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Spring State Machine, Spring API Gateway, and other popular Spring technologies/services
- Typescript, NodeJS, Prisma, Typeorm, NestJS, Express, NextJs, JavaScript, ReactJS
- Kotlin with SpringBoot, Quarkus
- Domain Driven Designs, Functional and Reactive Programming techniques
- Strong understanding of the Blockchain, Web3, dApps, and the Ethereum Virtual Machine, EVM
- System application design, Microservices architecture, Internal and external service communications using messaging services like RabbitMq, Kafka, JMS, etc
- Database Management (MongoDB, MySQL, DynamoDB, Postgres, CassandraDB), and also usage

### with ORM tools

- Docker, Webpack, AWS services including EC2, DynamoDB, Aws Api Gateway, Elastic Beanstalk, etc
- API integrations with third party services, npm package creation, updates and management
- Version Control Systems; Git, Github, Gitlab

### **Education**

**B.Sc** – Agriculture (Economics), University of Ilorin, 2016

### **Certifications and Courses**

**Understanding Typescript - Udemy** 

The Complete NodeJS Developer Course - Udemy

Java Programming Masterclass covering Java 11 & Java 17 - Udemy

Complete NestJS Course; NestJS Zero to Hero - Udemy

The Complete Java Development Course -Udemy

Learn DevOps: AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform and Azure DevOps - Udemy

**Building Restful APIs with Kotlin and Spring Boot - Udemy** 

**Event Driven Microservices - Udemy** 

Spring Framework 6: Beginner to Guru - Udemy

The Complete Elixir and Phoenix BootCamp - Udemy

SpringBoot MicroServices with Spring Cloud: Udemy